(DJ) Daniel B Richardson Jr.

Erie, CO • 720-419-5539 • dj.b.richardson@pm.me • https://linkedin.com/in/dj-b-richardson

Overview

10+ years' experience in DevSecOps, HW/SW engineering, and product/project management. Proven record of leading cross-function teams, and delivering secure, reliable, and scalable automated systems.

Skilled Platforms and Tools

CI/CD & IaC: GitHub/Lab, ArgoCD, Terraform, Ansible	Atlassian: Jira, Confluence, Zephyr
Containers & Orchestration: Docker, Helm, Kubernetes	OS: Linux (RHEL 7/8), Windows 8-12
Cloud & laaS: AWS(EC2, EKS), vmWare(vSphere, VCF)	Languages: C/C++, Python, SQL, Javascript

Experience

Lockheed Martin | DevSecOps Engineer – Product Owner of Site Reliability (2020–Present)

- Lead Agile DevSecOps team strategy, priorities, and execution for mission-critical ground systems.
- Established Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) subteam, standards, and incident readiness.
- Deployed microservices with Helm/Ansible on K8s; automated provisioning on AWS and vSphere.
- Develop NIST SP 800-171/53 guided TLS management automation for VM's & k8s ingress/egress
- Architect design and install docs for Space-to-Ground sites; coordinated across HW/SW/NW teams.

Promethean Hive | DevOps & Full-Stack Engineer (2023–Present) https://demo.experiencebylocals.com

- Developed and maintained React/TypeScript frontend, Django Python backend, PostgreSQL DB.
- Integrated 3rd party API suite (Auth0, Google Maps, CometChat, Stripe)
- Implemented cloud-native CI/CD via Terraform, Kubernetes, and GitOps workflows.

Audit Logistics | Senior Project Manager (2013–2018)

• Led a team through ~95 Agile projects annually, using proprietary auditing SW for data tracing

Education & Certificates

- Dual M.S. Computer Science & Engineering Management, Univ. of CO. Boulder (in progress)
- B.S. Computer Science, Univ. of CO. Boulder

TS/SCI Clearance (Active) CompTIA Security+ CompTIA Network +